A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Program Committee FA945
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Program Committee
1933-1973
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA945
1.32 Cubic Feet 3 boxes
3 boxes.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for scholarly research, with select materials currently missing/unavailable as noted.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 537
Life sciences; Medicine, Preventive; Biology -- Research; Science -- Study and teaching; Medical technology; Medical research; Medical education; Medical sciences; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Program Committee, 1933-1957
  Scope and Contents note
  Rockefeller Institute Staff meetings, Program Committee notebook.
  Arrangement note
  1933-1954 Notebook; 1954-1957 chronologically.
  - "Staff Meetings", 1933 March 24-1954 May 28 (Box 1)
    A listing of staff meetings which were held weekly during the academic year, citing the name of lecturer and subject. Beginning November 1935 the record includes the names of the officers elected to the "Program Committee"
    Where the weekly meeting is not held the lack is indicated and reason given.
    Starting 1953 Special Lectures in addition to Staff Meetings were instituted and these are also listed.
  - Notebook, 1954 June-1957 May (Box 1)
    In June 1954 Dr. Vincent P. Dole was elected chairman of the Program Committee for Staff Meetings and Dr. Herbert Jaffe was elected secretary. The notebook which the committee maintained and presented to the Archives has been divided into three folders by date: 1954/1955; 1955/1956; 1956/1957. Included is correspondence with the administration on plans and budget allowances and with invited speakers; schedules and listings of lectures and demonstrations; mailing lists and suggestions from staff members.
- Faculty Committee on Lectures, 1956-1973
  Biographical/Historical note
  In 1956/1957 as the scope of activities for faculty and staff on the campus grew a formal faculty committee to plan lectures, colloquia; thesis presentations and seminars was established. The Committee was disbanded after the 1972/1973 academic year. In the early years the faculty members who were elected to the posts of chairman and secretary carried on the activities making arrangements through correspondence. By 1961/1962, Pamela Lee (an administrative assistant to the President) took over from the Vice-President the function of coordinator as far as dates, announcements and honoraria were concerned though it was left to the scientists to suggest speakers and topics and to issue invitations. This continues the records which the old program committee deposited in the Archives.
  Minutes of meetings; correspondence; payments of honoraria.
  Arranged in chronological order.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition note
  Date received or inventoried: April 1980.
  - 1956-1957-1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Minutes of Committee meetings; correspondence relating to meetings and elections; some lists of planned events; some annual reports.
  - Announcements to Faculty from the Faculty Committee on Lectures (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Untitled
    Announcements, correspondence with lecturers and with University administration and with the accounting office. Some years have complete listings of programs; some years have very little information.
    - 1955-1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1959-1960 (missing) (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Unavailable.
    - 1960-1961 (missing) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - untitled
    Some listings, some correspondence with lecturers and with the administration and with the accounting office. The records are not very complete. These records should be used with CALENDAR OF EVENTS to obtain a more complete view and record of the various activities on the campus.
    - 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Scattered holdings, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Scope and Contents
      1967-1968 and 1968-1969 are NOT in the collection.
    - Scattered holdings, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Scattered holdings, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)